hey piano players I'm Milo over the past
13 years of playing and teaching piano
I've noticed some points there are
common in every piano beginner things
that slow down your progress as well
that's why today I will share with you
in just a couple of minutes a huge
shortcut that will help you avoid so
much frustration to get faster and
better results as a piano beginner so
let's
diary for beginners the golden Ru is
only learn new things that you can apply
right away play more think less don't
spend your precious time trying to
memorize things you are not going to use
instead leave room to try variations
that means play more the things you
already know for example let's say
you'll only know the S major scale so
try different
[Music]
patterns try to play jumping around
or even two songs
[Music]
through these variations for every
single thing you already
[Music]
know over the past years I've been
seeing so many students upset because
they know the notes but the song still
doesn't sound beautiful what I mean by
that for example in this song I play the
correct notes but it still sounds boring
[Music]
this happened because I played Without
dynamics that means without emotion a
really good analogy for that it's talk
if I say to you I'm really
[Music]
happy probably you won't believe me the
same thing happens with music no
Dynamics no emotion even as a piano
beginner you need to try those
variations those Dynamics right away try
different volumes different key
pressions and so on like this
[Music]
we can say it's going to take a while to
master this but trust me it's worth
every second we spend on it and by the
way if you enjoy this lesson please
consider to subscribe to this channel
completely free for you to game change
for me and if you are looking for a
piano course especially for beginners I
will leave the link of my course in the
description down
[Music]
below you don't have to wait until the
perfect moment
to start using the sustained padle as a
beginner you need to start using the
sustained padle right away and the
reasons for that are simple the padle is
part of the instrument it makes you
sound so so much beautiful and will gain
freedom to play listen the difference
between the song with and without the
pattle
[Music]
a good way to start using the pattern
right now it's playing measure per
measure
[Music]
chords two
chord or when you feel that sound is
getting mddy
[Music]
unfortunately you won't be able to keep
your motivation as high as as possible
for a full year in everything you do in
your life that's the reason you need
goals and a plan to achieve those goals
for example let's say my goal for a full
year is play piano at least 100 times
and my plan to achieve that will be play
at least three times per week other
thing you need to know exactly what
you're going to play for example 25% of
my time I will play exercise for hand
[Music]
coordination 15% learn new things to
level
up 50% of my time playing songs
[Music]
and the 10% left it's completely free
[Applause]
[Music]
I've been receiv messages like this from
students in the course every day oh I
spent two weeks on the song I've been
trying to play this song for a while so
much time on this song and here is the
truth probably you aren't study
correctly and to fix that follow this
framework to learn new songs or specific
Parts first only learn the right
[Music]
hand second the left hand
third play the both hands together but
just trying to figure out how to fit the
notes don't worry about the tample
[Music]
yet fourth is still play with the both
hands together but in this time with the
temple
[Music]
and for some cases keep this in mind
some songs will require more time from
you than others simple as that just
enjoy your journey give yourself room to
learn this instrument it's a completely
new language and to keep learning this
instrument just click on this video here
so thank you for watching and they see
the next tutorial C